such a beautiful evening
i'm sitting here and i'm i live
probably like an eight minute walk from
here
and every time i'm here i swear i have
this thought every single time i'm here
i'm like
why do i go one day without coming here
this is just
awesome i think that almost every single
time
i come here
and i definitely don't come every day
but it's so obvious that i
would if i was present to this
oh well obviously so interesting
and i i there's something about
beauty right that is like that
it's like there's a there's the
remembering of what was beautiful
and i think to myself when i remember it
in some sense i carry the being of that
beauty with me
in fact i probably owe my life to
the experiences of beauty in some in
some respects
there's a way in which when i go back
and look at that painting or
like look at this this ocean
i'm like whoa when i was thinking about
that
before i came here i thought i was
actually thinking about that
but now that i'm here and i'm looking at
this painting or this
sunset or this lake or whatever the
the beauty is that i'm apprehending in
the present
i'm clear i was not thinking about this
this is this and there's always a sense
of like well this time
right i'll remember
how's it also the other experience i
have that with oftentimes
um is with like taking hallucinogens
i don't know how many i think almost
every time i've had this experience of
where
you know i'll
i'll take it and the effect of it will
start coming on
and then i'll remember a couple like
you know right before i took it
and and it become obvious to me that
oh i thought when i was thinking about
this experience that i was actually
thinking about it but that i wasn't
thinking about it at all
this is totally not what i was thinking
about and i thought i was thinking about
it
and then i usually would have the
experience of like you know i think
about that every time i
take a listen to jen and that becomes
really trippy you know
probably the people who watch this video
are probably the kinds of people that
will
know exactly what i'm talking about
and i just i think i really appreciate
that and just
like that there is something about
experience like the encounter with the
beautiful
that can't be captured by me
in fact it can't it so much can't be
captured by me
that even if i remember that it's not
captured by me when i'm
imagining the beautiful thing
there's something so original
so real
beauty
that i just like that it's so
it cannot be in some sense
you know taken or stored
in some way
you know and it's interesting on some
level
there is this aspect speaking of beauty
about i think almost maybe every
perception
or even the most simplest object
always in some way
speaks to beyond itself
if anything for example
i only see the front of it and i don't
see the back
right or maybe the little ink blot on
the paper in some way
points to the paper there's always this
this quality about perception right
that it as you tune
into it there's something not graspable
about it
but precisely and it's and it's beyond
itself
right it's
it'll always be beyond itself and i'll
never be able to fully capture it
right in some
i don't know atomistic cartesian way
let's say
maybe this is what i hear
john and chris talk about this so so
beautifully about
the sense of moreness
and and the experiences of beauty
exemplify this
in a in a very in fact i think they
probably teach us
this morning
there's beyond this
and that there's something about when i
notice
that when i get into relationship with
the
inexhaustible intelligibility
that's beyond the particular situation
that i'm looking at
that the particular it does not by
by apprehending it or sensing that
moreness
it doesn't take away from the situation
in fact it
animates the situation with suchness
being as such beauty as such
my wife's skin
in that particular moment her
infinite heart
shines through and yet then the skin
is just animating
in its particularity of that moment
oh there it is